YUGE ZHANG

4633 Glen Erin Dr, Mississauga, ON | C: 226-975-7144 | zhang1ks@gmail.com

GitHub: github.com/zhang1ks | Linkedin: linkedin.com/in/yugezhang | Portfolio: yuge-zhang.com

Professional Summary

I am currently an innovative Full Stack Software Developer at Micron Digital. Previously, I worked at LiveApp in Waterloo as a Mobile App Developer. I successfully obtained my master's degree Masters of Applied Computing at the University of Windsor. Utilizing my solid technical skills of various aspects and my good industrial experience, I am currently seeking the position Full Stack Developer or any other positions you think I might be a good fit for.

Core Qualifications

- Android, iOS and Web App Development (3 years+)
- Commonly Used Languages: Java (4 years+), Swift, Python, Node.js, PHP, Classic ASP, Html5, CSS3, Javascript, MySQL
- Previous Working Platforms & Tools: AWS, Android Studio, Xcode, Visual Studio, Pycharm, WordPress, GitHub, Microsoft Office, Photoshop, MySQLWorkbench, Putty, Eclipse, etc.
- Acquired Certifications: Advanced Software Engineer, Advanced Database Management Engineer (CEIAEC)

Experience

Android, iOS and Web App Developer Micron Digital:

06/2017 to Current Mississauga, ON

PasSport, PasSportMe, GrapplersApp, AbsolutePositionApp, MDWorkoutCounterApp, etc.

- The web app PasSport(passportme.com) is a Sports Management solution, a Social Media outlet, Event creation and Ticketing system, and a Crowdfunding platform for Athletes, Sports Fans, Club Owners, and Federation Administrators all-in-one. My responsibility was to customize new widgets and pages following the client's requirements(including classic asp files, HTML widgets, javascript functions, and MySQL operations), QA and fix existing issues. I migrated the entire project from our previous server to AWS to make it scalable and resilient. I configured everything needed for the project by myself, like the IIS server in the ec2 instance, Amazon Relational Database Service, load balancer and auto-scaling groups, etc.
- **PasSportMe (One-person project)** is a hybrid mobile app serving our web app(passportme.com). It has two versions: Android and iOS which have been respectively published by me on Google Play Store and Apple App Store. The mobile apps have more user-friendly features than the web app, like push notifications with precise click-to-redirect pages, more secured and easy-to-use login system and in-app camera access for social feeds. I also wrote the python scripts combining the PyFCM to send push notifications and keep them consistent for both mobile apps.
- **GrapplersApp (One-person project)** is a mobile app presenting web app(grapplersapp.com). Almost every function in **PasSportMe** has been set up here. Besides, more customized native features have been built.
- AbsolutePositionApp (One-person project) has web version(node.js) and Android version. It mainly
 provides the in-app Bluetooth connection with the Arduino combined chip (a semi-finished product of our
 company) and two-way data streams. It draws more precise real-time polylines on GoogleMaps API than
 GPS does. Users can set up a starting point shown as a pin on in-app Google Map which can be moved to
 the accurate spot they need before the app starts drawing routes.

- MDWorkoutCounterApp (One-person project) is a native Android app. It connects to another electronic product of our company which is a wearable sports band. The main function is to give the band wearers who are doing workouts more visual and dynamic feedbacks about every count or even every motion(presented as a dynamic percentage in rings) and an analysis report about the workout velocity, force, and power.
- Other Skills during the working period: Meeting and communicating with clients to make apps what they want, using photoshop to design specific images for projects, developing small apps in node.js, writing python scripts to improve work efficiency, implementing Stripe payment pages for our apps, etc.

Mobile App Developer LiveApp: Sports App with featured functions

10/2016 to 03/2017 Waterloo, ON

- Started with my research on resources like open camera app.
- Meeting the needs of the customer, designed and developed the sports app, including all layouts, activities/fragments, frames, and APIs.

Java Developer Tarena International Inc.

03/2013 to 07/2014 Hangzhou, China

- Completed training project JSP to create a basic data modification web.
- Developed JSP and Servlet.
- Built Front End using HTML, CSS, Javascript.
- Extensively involved in writing SQL queries and extract data from the database.

Education

Master of Applied Computing: Computer Science

09/2015 to 06/2017

ON, Canada

Bachelor of Science: Information Management and Information System

Hangzhou Dianzi University,

University of Windsor

09/2009 to 07/2013 Zhejiang, China